TOHO
Toho Co., Ltd.
A-frame, slow start.
Full extension.
A-Frame, stop.
Comms are good.
Everything looks good. Proceed.
Commence dive towards target point.
Target sighted!
Commence the investigation.
Doraemon
the Movie
............
m 1077 93 l 1184 93 1184 144 1077 144
New Nobita and the
Castle of the Undersea Devil
- The sea! The sea!
- The mountains, the mountains!
If we're going camping, the mountains are the best!
It's cuz you can't swim, right, Nobita?
Huh?! A-Absolutely not!
What about you, Shizuka-chan?
Being surrounded by greenery and fresh air...
Waking up to the chirping of birds...
The mountains are the best, aren't they?!
Marine activities, colorful corals, and fish!
No matter how you look at it, the sea is the best!
I guess so...
It is nice to go to the mountains once in a while...
Yay!
- It's two against two, huh?
- Heheh.
There's someone else too, right?
So, he'll be the one to decide!
- Ah!
- That's right!
In that case...
Haste makes waste!
- It's "Strike while the iron's hot"!
- W-Wait!
Doraemooon!
Created By
Fujiko F. Fujio
Kokoro no naka itsumo itsumo egaiteru
Deep inside my heart, I've always, always, been drawing
(egaiteru)
(Drawing!)
Yume wo noseta jibun dake no sekai chizu
My own world map filled with all of my dreams
Character Design         Yuki Togashi
Mechanical Design    Tsutomu Suzuki
Shintaro Nagisa
Prop Design        Ayumi Nagaki
(Takekoputaa)
(Bamboo Copter!)
Direction
Tetsuro Karai
Tetsuya Wakano
Shingo Okano
Sora wo tonde toki wo koete tooi kuni demo
Flying through the sky, through time, and even to distant lands
Doa wo akete hora ikitai yo imasugu
So open the door, hey, I wanna go right now!
Concept Design              Airi Ando
Art Director    Eiko Nakamura
Art Setting          Yuri Sanami
(Dokodemo Doaa)
(Anywhere Door!)
Otona ni nattara wasurechau no kana?
When we grow up, will we forget these memories?
Cinematography    Takashi Suehiro
VFX                Sota Oya
Son'na toki ni wa omoidashite miyou
When that day comes, let's all try to remember
Editing      Toshihiko Kojima
Sharararara
Shalalalala
Recording Director   Akiyoshi Tanaka
SFX      Masaya Kitada
Boku no kokoro ni
Inside my heart
Itsumade mo kagayaku yume
Is an ever-shining dream
Doraemon
Music    Takayuki Hattori
Sono poketto de kanae sasete ne
You'll make it true with your pocket, won't you?
Sharararara
Shalalalala
Uta wo utaou
Let's all sing a song
Script    Isao Murayama
Min'na de saa te wo tsunaide
Everyone, let's all hold hands together
Doraemon
Sekaijuu ni yume wo sou afuresasete
Let the world overflow with dreams!
Director   Tetsuo Yajima
Hotttt...
- The sea!
- The mountains!
Doraemon, the mountains, right?!
Definitely the sea!
The mountains are great too!
The sea, right?!
Which one, Doraemon?!
What are you talking about?
We're all thinking of going camping.
But we're split on where we wanna go.
Yer goin' too, right?
You have the deciding vote, Dora-chan!
It's definitely the mountains!
The sea, right?!
Summer means going to the beach, right?!
Mountains!
Hey, hey, Doraemon...
The light filtering in through the gaps in the trees...
Definitely the mountains!
We can smash watermelons on the beach...
Snorkeling... and other stuff like that.
In the mountains, we can have a
barbecue and go hiking, right?
- Hey, Doraemon...
- Doraemon!
- Dora-chan.
- Doraemooon!
SHUT UP!
Why's he so angry?
What a mood-killer.
Hey, what about the camping trip?
So long as Doraemon's like that...
Hey, let's cool off at yer place.
Eh... You're coming?
Everyone's irritable due to the heat.
Let's talk about it some other time.
See you.
Hah... it's supposed to be summer vacation too.
Everyone's split up...
The shipwreck occurred approximately 450 years ago.
Loaded up with Incan treasures,
it's believed this ship was lost at sea en route to Spain.
In Japanese yen, it is approximately 20 trillion yen.
Gold and ornaments were onboard...
20 trillion yen?!
Careful consideration is underway
on whether to raise the wreck...
I know a place where we can enjoy
both the sea and the mountains!
A place like that exists?
But... isn't this an ordinary sea?
Where're the mountains?
It's right here.
At the bottom of the sea,
the sea floor!
Mountains on the sea floor?
What's this? Hahah, it's cool!
It's an Underwater Buggy.
Now, let's explore the
underwater mountains and plains!
Now, get on.
- Oh right. Use this first.
- What're those?
Gill Tubes.
If you put these in your nose,
you can breathe underwater.
Huh?! We're going to dive?!
Now, it's fine, it's fine.
Now, let's go!
Forward!
Greetings.
What?
I booted up the Underwater Buggy's computer.
Autopilot and Guide please.
Understood.
I will scan the surrounding area.
The Pacific Ocean, off the coast of Japan.
This is the continental shelf.
Continental shelf?
Are you unfamiliar with continental shelves?
It refers to a flat area of land
extending from the coast.
He's kinda annoying.
Well, it's a cheap, used item...
It's not flat at all!
This is a continental slope.
This continues for several kilometers,
all the way to the sea floor.
This is some good learning
for you, Nobita-kun.
It's kinda dark... and it's getting cold.
Of course.
We are almost at a distant of 200 meters
which means we are in the ocean depths.
Because hardly any sunlight reaches here.
The water temperature remains low.
Then, it's about time...
Adapting Light
Pretty!
Your body has adapted to the ocean depths.
For real! It's not cold and I can see really well.
In the 22nd century, we'll be visiting planets
that humans simply cannot survive in.
The Adapting Light lets you
adapt to any environment.
Even if you dive 10,000 meters,
it's the same as if you're lying under the Sun.
You don't even need the Gill Tubes anymore.
Really? Hah...
It's true! I can breathe!
However, the effect lasts for only 24 hours.
Humans have it hard, do they not?
You need to rely on gadgets for every single thing.
In that respect, I am fine even in the ocean depths.
Due to my water pressure-resistant,
variable plastic body,
my size and shape are completely customizable!
Geez!
But you don't need to shrink all of a sudden!
I just wished to demonstrate my features.
What else can you do?
I am very fast.
How is it?
Amazing!
Wait! Stop! Stop!
- We're running out of ground!
- Don't worry.
It can hover too?
Attitude control thrusters.
A manufacturer option.
What does that mean?
That it has a lot of features.
Eek! Are we really on Earth?
This is the Japan Trench.
Nobita-kun, look ahead.
Wow! A mountain under the sea!
See? I told you, didn't I?
This way, we can enjoy both the
sea and the mountains, right?
Hmm...
It's rugged, and not quite
like the mountains on land...
I wonder if Shizuka-chan will like this?
- Shizuka-chan?
- She's my friend.
F-r-i-e-n-d?
What is that?
Hmm... a friend is...
Yeah! A person you're close to.
What does 'being close' mean?
Being close is...
It's being close!
That's not an answer.
F-r-i-e-n-d...
Buggy, around here should be good.
Wow, what a great view!
The location is perfect, so...
For what?
Delicious Clam!
What kinda gadget is this?
The Delicious Clam
is a gadget for observing deep-sea creatures.
Deep-sea creatures are attracted to light,
so it releases specially formulated,
delicious, glowing plankton.
They'll come one after another.
We're not getting a lot of visitors, though?
It's not that fast.
Deep-sea creatures are energy-efficient.
Many of them are slow to move.
Are there any gadgets that can speed it up?
Not really.
Lots of them will be there when we camp though.
Hmm... I see.
All that's left is to get everyone here!
A mountain on the sea floor?
Yeah! It's an amazing view that
you'll never see on the surface!
We can see deep-sea creatures...
We can go hiking
and drive around in the Underwater Buggy!
Wow! That's lovely!
The deep sea?!
That's a yes from me!
Well, that works.
Let's raise that treasure ship we saw on the news!
No way...
The lifting operation has already begun.
What, is it too late then?
But camping on the sea floor
is a pretty rare experience.
It's settled! Let's go to the deep sea!
Yay!
Huh?!
You haven't done your summer
homework yet, have you?
You're not going camping
until you've finished.
Summer vacation will be
over by the time I finish!
Mom's right, do your best.
I understand!
I'll finish my homework quickly!
We were all divided, but now
we've finally come to a decision!
We're definitely going camping!
That's the spirit!
Nobita-kun?
I'm worried about your future!
Nobita-kun! Do your best!
Don't stop working!
Don't get distracted!
Hang in there!
Don't give up on yourself!
You can definitely do it!
It'll be alright!
Go for it, Nobita! Go!
Go for it... Hm?
Enough!
My head's gonna explode!
Ah... what are you doing?
Geez...
You've only finished two problems?!
And they're wrong too...
It's impossible for me anyways!
It's okay, it's okay!
I guess I'm not going
anywhere for summer vacation...
Today will be another day of
scorching summer heat.
Take care against heatstroke...
Mom.
Can he do it when he comes
back from camping...?
I... I guess not, huh.
I'll make him do it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah...
Continuing...
News about a shipwreck off
the coast of Bermuda.
Early yesterday morning...
The sunken ship, on which salvage operations
had begun, seems to have disappeared.
The cause is unknown.
Oh my...
Giaaan!
What's with the hurry?!
Did you see the news?
The treasure ship has disappeared!
Ah, seems so.
How are you so calm?
The ocean is vast, you know?
When something goes missing,
it's not something you can easily find!
Ya don't have 'ta state the obvious!
That... is... why...!
We'll find the ship ourselves!
If we received 10% of the 20 trillion yen as a reward...
We'd get 2 trillion yen!
2 trillion yen?!
Hey, when are we going camping?
About that...
Huh? You're all here?
Nobita-san, Dora-chan told us everything.
We can't go camping till
you finish your homework?!
Hurry and finish it!
It's impossible for me to finish it.
I'll explain anything you
don't understand.
- Really?
- Yeah, so do your best.
The sea floor is a mysterious world!
Dreams and adventures await us!
That makes me motivated!
Then, get on with it!
O-Okay!
Oh, perfect. This is about the deep sea.
The anglerfish...
uses its light to lure creatures that become its prey.
- You wanna see the real thing, right?
- I want to! I want to!
Don't stop, or I'll hit ya!
Everyone's working towards a single goal.
How wonderful.
Mom, Mom!
Look!
My homework is done!
Oh?
You did a great job.
You can do it if you try!
Can I go camping?
Yes! Have fun!
Yay!
- Yay!
- Alright!
- Dora-chan.
- Hm?
Take care of them, okay?
You got it, Mom!
Radar contact ahead, Captain.
I'm checking it out now!
Get them on the radio, immediately!
Aye, sir. Trying to raise them now.
It's a sailing vessel, sir!
No response on radio, sir. Still nothing.
Sound the danger signal!
Aye, sir!
Hard to starboard!
All hands on deck! Brace for impact!
And hurry! As soon as possible. Now, now!
Off the coast of Brazil,
the Queen Elise made contact with a sailing ship
According to the ship's captain,
based off the sailing ship's trajectory and speed,
it is unlikely to be an abandoned vessel.
That's creepy.
The sea is scary, huh?
- Nobita-saaan!
- Nobita!
Nobita!
W-We're off!
- Be careful.
- Have a nice trip.
Isn't this great?
- Yo!
- Good morning!
Shh! Things are looking stormy.
Everyone, over here!
But it's bright and sunny?
- What's wrong?
- Why are you so restless?
We need to go before
Mom's mood changes!
Let's hurry and go!
But... uwah!
We're already at the ocean!
What's goin' on, Doraemon?!
- Don't worry about it!
- Let's go!
Now, let's begin our journey to the sea floor!
It's fine, just try breathing.
- Amazing!
- I can breathe!
It's thanks to the Adapting Light!
Welcome to the heart of the Pacific Ocean!
So many fish!
It's like a giant aquarium!
It's such a luxury to be this close... Hm?
It's like it's blessing our departure!
That was a great sight.
What's this?
Shizuka-chan, it's the Underwater Buggy.
Nobita's friend, Shizuka-san?
- You can talk?!
- Yes.
Why are you being that casual with me?!
(Not using honorifics (san/kun) with people you
aren't close to is considered rude.)
What's your name?
My chassis number is S83-312.
My model name is "Underwater Variable Size Buggy Car"
So, can I call you Buggy-chan?
Buggy-chan...?
Yeah!
Nice to meet you, Buggy-chan!
- Nice 'ta meet ya.
- Nice to meet you!
It is nice to meet you.
Take us to that place.
Understood.
Please hold on tight.
Let's go!
Wow!
Hey, what's that?
A goblin shark.
It can open its jaw wide, and the
speed at which it lunges is about
3 meters per second.
Is it fast?
Compared to me, no.
Look, something's hanging off that.
A Gibberichthys latifrons.
Sounds like some kinda food!
Buggy, what's that?
Is it walking?
Is it a fish?!
That is a sea toad.
Cute!
Nobita, there!
It's a Pacific footballfish!
Even you know some, Nobita?
- D-Don't make fun  of me!
- Hahahah!
Hey, let's go to the Bermuda Triangle!
What's that?
Let's go find that lost treasure!
If we find it, we'll get 2 trillion yen!
2 trillion yen?!
Bermuda? No way!
It's on the other side of the planet!
We can't go that far!
I can do it in a day.
- Really?!
- Wow!
No means no!
We've already decided on where we're staying for the night.
If you want to go on a treasure
hunt that badly...
Treasure Hunt Counter!
There are precious rare metals in the seabed.
Rare metals?
They're used in electronics.
They're metals that are sold for a high price.
Examples include manganese and gold.
Gold?!
It'll tell you if there's
treasure within 100 meters.
Alright! Let's find 'em all!
Oh treasure, where are you~?
This is exciting, isn't it?
We might become super-rich!
Oh, did I find it?!
It's here...?!
A tire?!
A plastic bag...
A plastic bottle...
Seriously! Is the ocean one big trash can?!
Doraemon, this gadget isn't broken, is it?!
Come on...
They must have been dropped
from the surface, correct?
Plastics do not decompose in the soil.
They will remain for a long time.
That's strange...
Everyone!
This is big! Look at this!
It's a rare metal! A rare metal!
Wow, amazing!
- Seriously?
- Ya did it!
Buggy, can you analyze it?
Of course.
The material is an alloy of palladium,
nickel, molybdenum, chromium,
stainless steel, and titanium.
However, judging by the level of corrosion,
I estimate it is about 7,000 years old.
7,000 years old?!
However, it is a genuine rare metal.
- Woah!
- Really?!
Amazing!
Yay!
Let me touch it!
This is crazy!
There must be some mistake.
There's no way something like
that existed 7,000 years ago.
But that is what the analysis results show.
I have received an alarm
about volcanic activity.
Activating self-defense program.
The shaking will commence in 3, 2, 1...
It's an earthquake!
Everyone, get on!
Hurry!
Hey! We'll get crushed!
Shut up! Do not waste my memory!
Buggy! Forward! Forward!
- Nobita-san!
- Nobita!
A... A squid?!
Go back! There was a huge squid!
It was dozens of meters long!
Why're ya talkin' about
that at a time like this?!
Don't ask the impossible!
Buggy, get us somewhere safe, quick!
I am on my way right now!
We should be safe now that we're this far.
Hey, look!
Ah, it's our mountain!
We've arrived.
Amazing!
So many!
Why only here?
I've lured them over with the Delicious Clam.
Ah! Hey, doesn't that one look like Doraemon?
Oh, it does!
They look alike!
We don't!
Ah, this little one is?
That is a leftvent seadevil.
A male is attached to its body.
It will never leave it again.
What's that?
Deep-sea creatures are all
so interesting, aren't they?!
Let's camp here today...
Tent Apartment!
When you inflate it...
Now, come on in, come on in.
This is the living room.
Wow!
- It's nice!
- Pretty!
Well, it's a pretty decent grade.
There are private rooms too.
Hahah! It's so fluffy!
So, this is Gian's bed now, huh?
We can go outside.
There's one important thing
I need to tell you.
It'll be bad if you forgot about
this while living underwater.
- Huh?
- Hm?
First, when you enter,
close the door behind you.
Press this button.
Wait until all the water has
drained before defecating.
Oh, you're talking about the toilet.
This is serious!
Just try doing it in the water!
It'll mix with the surrounding water...
Dora-chan, the shower is...?
We're already underwater.
Oh, right.
Now, let's have a barbecue for dinner.
Barbecue?!
In the Underwater Cooking Machine,
insert the barbecue order card...
Wait three minutes.
How did you start a fire underwater?
It's an Underwater Campfire.
But the brightness doesn't
really fit the mood, does it?
What is a 'mood'?
Hmm... how do I explain it...?
Oh! I almost forgot.
Lights-Out Bulb!
Um... here should do.
When you put this on,
the surroundings become dark.
Pretty...
The mood has gotten way better!
Mood... you say.
Mmm... delicious!
This is good quality meat!
It's so soft.
It looks like meat, but it's actually
made of processed plankton.
Huh?! From that Delicious Clam?
Yep, they're edible.
Woah... it definitely looks like meat to me.
This is the first time I've
eaten something like this!
Whatever it is,
it's delicious!
Yeah!
It's similar to the filet mignon I ate in France!
Hey, what are we doing tomorrow?
Let's search for that ship in the Bermuda Triangle!
No way!
But why...?
Hey, where exactly is that?
From here, we would have to
cross America to reach it.
But it's strange, isn't it?
That a sunken ship just disappeared.
In Bermuda, anything is possible.
Why?
Haven't you heard of the Devil's Triangle?
For many years, numerous ships and
airplanes have disappeared in that area.
Huh?
Where do they go after disappearing?
There are various theories!
Like it being a gateway to the fourth
dimension or them being abducted by aliens.
Aliens?!
Why don't we try and solve that mystery together?
You say that, but you're after
the treasure, aren't you?
No matter how many times you say it,
no means no!
What a hard-headed jerk!
It'll be too late once we get into trouble!
Now, now...
Mm... Mommy...
Ah... why do I have to sleep with Buggy...
All cuz I lost at rock-paper-scissors...
This is my first time sleeping
with a human.
I'm sleeping now.
Good night.
Buggy?!
Geez, and I thought I was a bad sleeper.
This is a disaster!
Gian and Suneo are missing!
What happened?
Where did they go?!
Huh? Where's Buggy?
Gwahahahahah!
We're gonna become filthy rich!
Is it really possible 'ta
get there in a single day?
I am very fast...
But are you really sure?
Of course!
Boys like us aren't afraid
of a little danger, right?!
They left here three hours ago!
This is bad, this is really bad!
What's so bad about it?
The effect of the Adapting Light
only lasts for 24 hours!
There's less than 30 minutes left!
Hm? Hey, it's getting kinda dark...
Come to think of it...
Huh? It's hard to breathe...
The effect of the Adapting Light
is beginning to wear off.
Th-Then...!
Let's follow them!
They're probably heading for the Bermuda Triangle!
What happens when the effect wears off?!
It will become pitch-black and
you will not be able to breathe.
The immense water pressure will completely crush you.
Why didn't you tell us?!
I asked, "Are you really sure?"
But you said you "aren't afraid of a little danger"...
Quit screwin' around!
Mommy!
I know!
I wonder if we can use the Obtaining Bag?
It won't work!
Buggy is speeding along at breakneck speeds!
It's like trying to catch a speeding
bullet with your bare hands!
The Anywhere Door?
It's still sitting above the sea.
We can't get it back in 30 minutes!
It's pitch black...
I can't see a thing...
Nobita-kun!
The motors are redlining...
We will soon cross the Eastern Pacific Rise.
They fell off...
Are you going to die?
Humans are arrogant, but...
They are quite weak creatures, are they not?
Doraemon!
What's wrong?
Time's... up.
- Huh?!
- Come on!
It's my fault!
I'll break myself as punishment!
Calm down!
This won't solve anything!
If I'd just been more careful,
we could've gotten them back... Hm?
We could've used the Obtaining Bag...
to obtain the Anywhere Door.
Why didn't you think of that sooner?!
Calm down, Nobita-san!
- I can hear something.
- You can?
It's from the direction the two of them went in.
What happened?
Buggy!
Buggy! Are you alright?
Gian! Suneo!
They haven't been flattened by the water pressure...
Why?
God, please!
Unless you want to hear Gian's terrible, awful singing...
Please save him!
Nobita-kun...
Who said my singing is terrible and awful... hey!
- Hm? Gian!
- Suneo-san!
You're both alive!
Uh... yeah, I guess we're still alive.
It's a miracle!
You're so clumsy, Doraemon.
The effect of the Adapting Light isn't over, right?
That can't be...
We had an awful experience cuz of him!
I went because I was ordered to go.
I even asked for confirmation.
What did you say?!
Yer pretty cheeky fer a second-hand buggy!
Hey!
Now you've done it.
Humans are always like this.
Ya wanna fight?
I'm gonna beat ya to a pulp!
If you can.
Wait! Calm down!
Stop! Both of you!
Buggy-chan is right!
It isn't his fault for doing as he was told!
Shizuka-san...
Isn't it your fault for going without
telling us in the first place?!
I hope you two never do something this rash again!
We were wrong...
I'm sorry.
Alright!
That settles it then.
We've arrived! We're at the Mariana Trench.
That famous one?
What's this?
A trench is a valley on the ocean floor.
This is the Mariana Trench, the deepest in the world.
Come, let's go!
- Yahoo!
- Hold on!
Huh?! Buggy, wait!
No way!
(11km or 6.8 miles)
The Mariana Trench is approximately 11,000 meters deep.
You'd have to stack Mt. Fuji atop Mt. Everest
at the bottom to see their peaks from the top.
Hm... I don't get it.
The deepest dive ever recorded by a human is
approximately 10,000 meters.
We're gonna surpass that record!
To a place nobody's been to before!
We're going there!
That's right!
Ladies and gentlemen!
Welcome to the deepest point on Earth!
It doesn't feel that different.
The top is blurry and hard to see.
Hey, hey, hey! Since we're here,
let's take a commemorative photo!
Sounds good!
It'll be proof that we've reached the deepest part!
Deep Sea Camera!
Humans are inconvenient, aren't they?
If you record it in the memory of an electronic
brain, then you can view it anytime, right?
We can't do it like you.
Seriously, yer ruinin' the mood.
Since memories are unreliable, we preserve them by turning them into tangible things.
Now, cheese!
It's good!
Perfect!
Make some copies for us later!
Yeah!
Alright, Suneo. Let's go exploring!
Okay!
Hey, Dora-chan.
Is it fine if I take some sand as a souvenir?
See? Photos are good too, right?
- Hey!
- Hm?
Everyone, come here!
What happened?
Hey, look at this!
This is a great discovery!
There's no mistaking it!
It's the same ship I saw on the news!
Let's check it out!
Wait!
Let's go too, Nobita-san!
Huh?! It's dangerous!
I'm going too!
It's in pretty bad shape.
Oh, it's open!
Looks like we can go inside through here.
Where's the treasure?
20 trillion yen~
- It's a little scary.
- Geez...
Hey, there might be something weird around.
Just wait there, ya coward!
There's no way I'm going in!
Do whatever you want!
The insides are pretty run-down.
This is...
- ...gold, isn't it?!
- Huh?!
Lemme see.
It's real!
I wonder if someone has already taken the rest?
Come on, ya gotta be kiddin' me!
There must be more.
Let's find it, Suneo!
Yeah!
Can I ask you something?
What?
Why did Shizuka-san protect me?
I was never treated like that by my previous owners.
I guess she couldn't just leave you alone?
Shizuka-chan is a kind girl.
Couldn't leave me alone...
- Something's here!
- Eek!
S... S-S-S...
Skeleton?!
It looks quite old.
It might've been one of the ship's crew members.
Hey, everyone!
Did something happen?!
Are you alright...?!
S-Something's here!
This ship has no propulsion...
20 trillion yen has disappeared.
So, someone carried it here,
and they took the money too?
We were too late...
Can ya really transport a ship this big?
But it's right here, at the bottom of the Mariana Trench.
Help meee!
What the?!
What, is it an earthquake?!
What happened?
The mast is broken!
Where's Nobita-san?!
- Nobita-kuuun!
- Hey, Nobitaaa!
Over here!
Nobita-kun!
Here!
- Are you alright, Nobita-kun?
- Yeah.
Why're ya buried in a place like this?
I was attacked by a huge fish!
Did the fish destroy the boat?
Yeah, it did!
- A whale?
- Are there any this deep?
It's true!
There was a fish thiiis big!
Yer still on that?
Didn't ya say ya saw a huge squid yesterday too?
But I did see it!
Buggy, you saw it too, right?
I have not seen anything that
could be described as a fish.
- Just...
- Oh come on...
I guess Nobita was just mistaken after all.
The ship looked pretty damaged too, so...
But, it's true!
There was a massive fish!
Yeah, yeah. We get it, we get it.
Still, it's all so strange.
Hmm... there's no treasure, and
the ship's been moved.
We found metal that was 7,000 years old.
And a huge squid and a huge fish.
And the strangest of all...
The Adapting Light on Gian and Suneo.
It definitely should've worn off by then.
Yeah, I'm curious...
Who is it?
Buggy-chan.
What happened?
Do you have some time?
Shizuka-san, you want to know about the
Adapting Light incident with Gian and Suneo, right?
Yeah.
I saw it.
It is recorded in my memory.
Do you want to see it?
Huh? I can?!
Yes.
I will project the image.
Are you going to die?
Humans are arrogant, but...
In that case...
You were just watching quietly?!
There was no optimal solution.
I ran a simulation, but
death was an unavoidable outcome.
What's going on, Shizuka-chan?
Nobita-san.
Ain't that us?
Is it from that incident?
I will increase the projection size.
- Woah!
- What's that?!
I do not know.
I have all sorts of information
about the ocean.
But there is no data on this.
A person?!
The Adapting Light?!
That's it! It's the big fish I saw!
See? I told you!
We'll see that huge squid soon!
It's not a fish!
Fish can't shoot laser beams!
After that, I froze.
Why were ya holdin' onto somethin' that important...?!
Stop that, Takeshi-san!
Because I wasn't asked.
Quit screwin' with me!
Calm down, Gian!
This isn't the time for fighting!
Now, we have a new problem!
Who exactly saved you two?!
And why did they save you?!
There being others besides us on sea floor,
there's no doubt about it now.
Stop that, Gian.
N-N-N... Nobita-kun... slowly come over here.
Uwaaah! A squid!
Ah... see, I told you! I told you!
This isn't the time to celebrate!
Woah! Doraemon, pull something out!
Something... something...
Anywhere Door!
Ah, no way!
I'm not tasty! I'm not tasty!
- Nobita!
- Nobita-san!
Let go of Nobita-kun!
Shizuka-chaaan!
Small Light!
Let go! You...
Mommyyy!
Dammit!
Doraemon, what did you do?
No, it wasn't me.
- That's...
- It's the one from before...
Did they help us again?
Ah, thanks!
That was a close call again...
This is...?!
This is where you were born.
3.8 billion years ago,
the place where life first originated in the world...
was in the depths of the sea.
Eventually, they began living on land.
This was only 400 million years ago.
The fierce struggle for survival repeated.
Many kinds of species were born and went extinct.
Among them, some returned
from the land to the sea.
For example, whales,
dolphins, and seals.
And then...
We Undersea Dwellers.
Undersea Dwellers?
Doraemon!
Shizuka-chan!
Where are we?
I don't know.
I saw a weird dream.
Me too!
It was an educational dream.
You're...
To help people learn about us,
the Undersea Dwellers.
Then, it really was...!
My apologies.
I wasn't sure if I could trust you guys.
That was way too violent!
Violent? Surface Dwellers like
you have no right to say that.
Huh?!
We have witnessed the bloody,
war-filled history of the Surface Dwellers.
Being cautious is only natural.
But, after examining your brainwaves,
we have determined that you pose no danger.
We have decided to welcome you to our country.
I am El.
What do you mean?
Nobita, Shizuka, and Doraemon, right?
Still, this is troublesome.
I can't believe you're a robot...
You look like a dumbo octopus...
A dumbo octopus?
Absolutely not!
I'm a cat-type robot!
It'd be better to keep that a secret for now.
Huh? Why?
Also, where's Gian and Suneo?
And Buggy-chan too!
He was overheating. We are doing maintenance on him.
Where are the other two?
A psychiatric evaluation
diagnosed them as 'violent' and 'deceitful',
so they are being held in custody.
- Huh?!
- That's...!
- There must be a misunderstanding!
- They're good guys at heart!
Good guys?
Let us talk to them!
Hmm... follow me.
- Amazing!
- It's pretty!
A civilization like this exists on the sea floor...
This is the Mu Federation.
It's a short distance from the location of the sailing ship
you were investigating.
How did you...?
I've been keeping an eye on you all
since I found those two.
That's it!
When Gian and Suneo's Adapting Light wore off,
you helped them didn't you, El?
Ah, we call ours the Adap Light though...
Why did you help us?
How dare they shove people in a place like this?!
Let us out!
If ya don't...!
I'll smash and burn it all down...
We're underwater, that won't work!
These are those 'good guys'?
This is bad...
Oh, everyone!
Get us out of here!
I'll find a way to get you out!
Just wait a little more!
Oh! My friend of the heart!
In any case, I can't decide this on my own.
You should try talking to
the Prime Minister directly.
Absolutely not!
They are far too dangerous!
Simply being a Surface Dweller
makes you an unwelcome guest.
However, as per the laws of the sea floor,
defenseless intelligent lifeforms
are eligible for protection.
Those of you who pass the screening
will be bestowed citizenship.
You will spend your entire lives here.
Huh?!
You dragged us here by force!
We can't let the Surface Dwellers
find out about this place.
We won't speak of this to anyone!
So let us go home!
That's not allowed. According to the law, anyone who crosses the border without permission...
...is sentenced to death.
Don't worry, we won't harm you.
You'll get used to it quickly.
- Wait a second!
- Ah, Nobita-kun!
Feel free to use this space however you like.
However, please refrain from
going outside for the time being.
If anything happens, tell the people outside.
Bye then.
Ah... this is the worst!
Forget summer vacation, we're
stuck here for the rest of our lives!
That's not gonna happen.
Let's get outta here quickly!
- But, if we get caught?
- The death penalty!
That's way too dangerous!
Then, we just need to not get caught.
Who do you think I am?
Doraemon!
Just follow orders!
It's about time we replaced it with a new one.
Buggy-chan?
Sh... Shizuka-san?
Buggy, Shizuka-chan!
Hurry!
It's no good, it won't budge.
My friends of the heart!
Ya kept us waitin'!
Get off me already!
The Prime Minister, was he angry?
Why did you help them?
You could've just ignored it.
I don't know myself.
I just thought it was right.
I hope their arrival
doesn't provoke Poseidon...
- Come right away!
- What happened?
The Surface Dwellers have escaped!
- Huh?!
- What did you say?!
They've already noticed.
Getting ahead of them will be dangerous.
Now!
We've already been separated...
- Ah.
- Hm? What?
- Quiet.
- Hey, you!
Wah, we've been spotted!
Hold on!
- Uwah, sorry!
- Stop!
Where did they go?!
- This way!
- Huh?
They must still be nearby!
Thank goodness you're safe.
Seriously, where did you go?
Don't make us worry!
Sorry...
- Have you seen any Surface Dwellers?
- I haven't.
Let's go around from that side.
Ugh! Here too...
Are you all Surface Dwellers?
N-No we're not!
Stop!
We're looking for Surface Dwellers!
Have you seen them around here?
Surface-Dwellers?
Ah, I have!
- Heheheh.
- Really?!
Hold on! This old lady
had lied and said she went to Atlantis.
Come on, stop messing with us!
That's enough! Go!
Stop!
Stay hidden.
I'll take you close to the border.
Hey, are we going to be fine with her?
I'm not sure, but...
It seems safer than just running away.
We've arrived.
If you go straight through this
oyster field, you'll reach the border.
Once you've crossed the border,
security should be fairly lax.
Ah... hey, Nobita!
Let's go!
Why did you help us?
It seems like everyone hates us
Surface Dwellers down here.
There's bound to be someone
who thinks differently, right?
Don't take it personally; everyone's just scared.
They don't want to make a
certain someone angry, you see?
Hurry up, and don't get caught!
Hurry!
Nobita-kun, hurry!
Yeah.
What a stupid thing to do!
They're here!
What do we do, Doraemon?!
That's the border, right?
There's nowhere to hide!
Time for the Chameleon Cap to shine!
El! That's...?!
Found them!
Hurry! Hurry!
You guys! Surrender now!
El...
Hurry!
- They disappeared?!
- Huh?
Hey, what's going on?
We're in a hyperspace pocket
under the surface.
To El and the others, it looks
just like the Earth's surface.
Well, it's kinda like a one-way mirror.
Look, they're gone.
Even if they disappear, we know where they're headed!
Come, let's go!
As we move forward, the hyperspace
moves along with us.
Let's cross the border!
If they cross the border, there's
no escaping the death penalty.
The ocean trench ends here.
The Chameleon Cap can't move vertically.
What do we do?
We have no choice but to wait
for El and the others to leave.
Hey, look! That's what attacked me!
We've lost control!
El is...!
Please respond!
We were attacked by a Battlefish!
We're unable to fight back!
It looks like they can't move...
It's coming back!
Hold on, Gian!
I can't stand by and watch!
I'm helping them now!
Come at me!
I'm yer opponent!
What are you doing?!
- Us too!
- Yeah!
Geez!
Geez, I'm going too! Mommy!
It's useless! Run!
I'll catch ya!
- Doraemooon!
- Calm down!
Small Light!
Got it on the first try!
Take this!
Gotcha!
Geez! Get it away from me!
We did it!
Oh, yer safe!
Why did you come out?!
I'm... here to catch you guys!
Those who cross the border will
be sentenced to death...
So why did you come out?!
Now, there's no way I can...
Surface Dwellers!
Hands in the air!
You are completely surrounded!
Yeah, they're up!
Can there be anythin'
more stupid than this?!
If we had just hidden, we coulda escaped!
Who was the idiot that decided to jump out?!
Ah, it was me...
I'm an idiot! Idiot! Idiot!
What's going to happen to us...?
As El said, it's the death penalty, right?
Mommy!
Nobita, I have something that I want to ask you.
At a time like this?
Why are humans so irrational?
I have been watching you all for the past
few days, and I can't understand it.
If you hadn't come out earlier, then...
That's complicated.
Back then...
Even though I knew better, I
didn't make the 'correct' choice.
I just did what I thought was 'right'.
Is there a difference between 'right' and 'correct'?
There are times when there isn't.
What your heart thinks is right...
Isn't 'heart' your internal organ...?
No... it's different.
I don't understand what a 'heart' is.
'Right' and 'correct' aren't the same thing...
It's like...
a 'bug', isn't it?
We humans are complicated, aren't we?
There are many things that I don't know either...
The verdict regarding the five Surface Dwellers is that
in accordance with the laws of the Mu Federation, they are to be sentenced to death.
Are there any objections?
And with that, parliament is adjourned...
Wait a moment!
What?
No, it's just...
Please grant them amnesty...
They helped me without
regard for their own safety.
They are heroes!
Heroes? They're just naive...
Realizing they couldn't escape,
they probably thought they could
save you to gain your sympathy.
Is that the only way you can interpret it?
They couldn't just leave someone to die,
that could've been the reason they had...
It makes me ashamed to be a Undersea Dweller!
We can acknowledge their heroic actions.
However, rules are rules.
According to Mu's criminal code,
crossing the border is punishable by death.
That's ridiculous! It's a thousand-year-old law
that's smeared with oyster shells!
I understand.
These laws were created out of fear of Poseidon.
These laws were made to minimize the impact
of crossing the border, and of technology.
What are you trying to say?
It's my heart!
What's important is...
that at first, I didn't understand why I helped them.
But, when I looked at them, I realized.
I have a heart too!
A human heart!
Please calm down.
Have you forgotten what the Surface Dwellers have done?!
They pollute the ocean with sewage and plastic.
They mine for resources in the deep sea.
There's no room for sympathy for them!
Don'tcha think so?!
That's right!
Isn't this exactly the same as 50 years ago?!
Then, what about us?
We brush our fears under the rug, and refuse to confront the root of the problem!
We've come to view change as a negative thing!
If we'd listened to her, and trusted her without hesitation...
Perhaps, a different future awaited us!
Watch your mouth!
What happened?
I've a report!
The Bermuda Volcanic Zone Observatory
has issued a Level 5 activity alert!
The Devil's Castle has become operational!
We're displaying footage from the observatory!
This is the worst possible scenario.
The world is...
going to end.
It's a Level 5! Hurry!
Did something happen?
Oh, God.
Oh God of Navarre, ruler of the four seas.
Please stop the activity of the underwater volcano.
We no longer
have a way to stop it.
There is only one way.
Allow me to introduce you.
50 years ago,
Miss Triline, reported contact with Poseidon.
What does she have to do with this?
She may be the only one who has
returned alive from the Devil's Castle.
Let's hear her story again.
There was no evidence at the time.
Are you telling us to trust her?
It's too dangerous.
Has anyone else seen Poseidon?
Or visited Atlantis?
What we should do now is
not try and appease Poseidon.
And definitely not just sit and pray!
It's a long story, so let me sit down.
My back hurts.
Sorry, I didn't notice...
If you don't make a choice,
and just stand here praying,
we'll have no choice left but to
perish together with this country.
But if this woman's story is true...
We can stop Atlantis!
If it's true, it's a sliver of hope!
And if it's a lie, it's the end of the world.
It's one of those two!
Now is the time for change!
Prime Minister! Follow your heart!
Make the right choice!
Please, lady.
Could you please tell us about that time again?
Of course, that's fine, but...
Even if we could go to Atlantis,
they'd be just as powerful.
Whether we win or not...
I understand.
Besides us, there are some others
who hold the key to this future.
Ahhh! I don't wanna die!
Mommy!
We have a favor to ask.
Would you be willing to help us?
To save the world!
We need your strength.
Once more... help us!
- Ah!
- Grandma!
Did ya get caught cuz of us?
Don't worry. I'm glad you all are safe.
But, why are you here?
This person is Miss Triline.
She is an essential figure for this operation:
The capture of the Devil's Castle.
- Devil's Castle?
- Operation?
The Devil's Castle is
a fortress ruled by an AI named Poseidon.
Approximately 7,000 years ago, we,
the Mu Federation of the Pacific,
were at war with the Atlantic
Federation of the Atlantic Ocean.
I've heard it was a terrible war.
Robos and Battlefish were used.
7,000 years ago...
Then this...
How do you have that?
It belongs to our Mu Federation.
Seriously?!
So it's true...
I told you so!
During that time, Atlantis developed the Devil's Horns.
The Devil's Horns?
They are bombs powerful
enough to destroy the Earth.
So, they used them to threaten the Mu Federation into unconditional surrender.
But Mu still exists, doesn't it?
- Ya idiot!
- Can't you tell just by looking?
The experiment with the Devil's
Horns failed, and Atlantis fell.
Hold on! Didn't you just say they
could destroy the Earth...?
Atlantis had erected a barrier around themselves
to remain protected from the Devil's Horns.
This barrier stretches far into the heavens.
In a cruel twist of irony, it served to
contain the explosion within Atlantis.
It's the Bermuda Triangle!
But that's strange.
Doesn't that mean we should be at peace now?
The AI Poseidon survived.
If the territory of the Devil's Castle is disturbed,
it is programmed to fire the remaining Devil's Horns.
As long as we didn't bother it,
there wasn't any problem.
That's why we, the Mu Federation,
continued to avoid it.
But now, it is under threat.
An underwater volcano is about
to erupt near the Devil's Castle.
If it erupts, Poseidon may think
that it is under attack.
It will fire the Devil's Horns deployed outside the barrier.
Not even a single fish, insect, or blade of grass
will remain alive.
The Earth will...
become a dead planet.
That's why, we must stop Poseidon at all costs.
But... how?
Won't we have to sneak past the barrier and the Devil's Horns to reach Poseidon?
That's where Miss Triline comes in.
There's no one left who has met Poseidon.
However, Miss Triline...
50 years ago, she reported making
contact with Poseidon during a mission.
However, the Parliament at the time decided that
further investigation would only fuel public anxiety, and stopped pursuing the matter.
Her statement was declared to be false.
Man, I can't understand all these big words...
In simple words, based on her report,
we're heading for Poseidon.
Hmm... what did Grandma see at that time?
It'd be nice if we could see it too.
We can!
Image Light
What's that?
This is a gadget that lets everyone see
what's going on inside a person's mind.
Is that possible?
Grandma, please show us what happened that time.
During my mission,
I was attacked by a Battlefish, and crashed.
Soon after,
a robot soldier clad in metal armor arrived.
I believe they were called the Iron Cavalry.
They captured me...
and took me to Poseidon.
I thought I was going to die.
So that's Poseidon...
But, I managed to find an opportunity and escape.
Passing through rock crevices and chimney caves,
I finally managed to cross the barrier.
Luckily, a search party from Mu found me soon after.
They rescued me.
It truly was a miracle that I was able to escape.
Unbelievable...
Miss Triline.
This is rather belated but,
I offer my sincerest apologies for all the rudeness
I displayed to you up until now.
It's fine. Now go and save the world.
Yes, we will!
Team Abyss will take the lead and distract the Battlefish.
Yes sir!
And our Team Ventus will
neutralize the Devil's Horns in
preparation for the eruption.
And you all, together with El, must stop Poseidon.
Well then, I wish you all the best!
In the future where we've saved the world,
we'll definitely meet again!
We need to go faster, or we won't
make it before the eruption!
That's insane! I'm carrying six people!
Please, Buggy-chan!
If we don't make it in time, it's pointless!
The fate of the world rests on you, Buggy-chan!
You selfish jerk!
We're underwater.
The dirt will come off without scrubbing.
You drove with all your might.
Let me do this much.
You protected me, Shizuka-san,
you were kind to me...
My previous owners never did that to me...
I'm not your owner! I'm your friend.
Friend...
Oh?
The bolt...
There!
What's this...?
A charm. So that we're always safe when driving.
It's perfect! Now I can drive anywhere!
Shizuka-chan?
Huh? What're the two of you doin'?!
That's not fair!
Gian, Suneo, look!
- What's that?
- Isn't it cool?
Shizuka-san did it for me.
This is so that we're always safe while driving!
It's a charm!
That's great.
There aren't any Battlefish, huh?
Yeah, seems like they're doing a good job.
Is that the barrier?
We'll be in uncharted territory past this point.
This is the realm of Atlantis.
Let's test it out!
That's insane!
A frontal assault is impossible.
Miss Triline must've...
Buggy, is there a chimney cave around here?
I found one.
That must be it!
This is it, no doubt about it.
The temperatures are in the hundreds of degrees,
and it's filled with toxic gases.
We couldn't have advanced
without the Adapting Light.
Buggy, look out!
The only way is...
Can't we use Doraemon's
gadgets to move the rocks?
Gadgets...
I know!
Chameleon Cap!
That's a great idea!
Let's go in!
We have a report!
Preparations for firing the Demon Horns confirmed!
The number is approximately...
Over 60 missiles!
We'll be arriving at the barrier soon.
Hey, what if the barrier extends underground?
If that happens, we'll all be annihilated.
I'm sure we'll be fine!
Shizuka-chan!
Yeah!
60 meters to the barrier.
- Mommy!
- 50...
40... 30...
20... 10...
We've crossed it.
Yay!
Ah... hey, look.
It's like a graveyard fer ships and airplanes.
I get it! They hit the barrier and crashed!
The mystery of the Bermuda Triangle...
is this...?
Hey, something's coming!
It's the Iron Cavalry.
What creepy freaks.
Gian!
Ah... sound.
They react to sound.
Jet Mole.
They're going back.
They think they've defeated us.
- Please surface.
- Why?
We'll get caught!
They must be heading back to the Devil's Castle.
Alright, let's hurry and chase after them.
Can we count on you, Buggy?
Buggy?
Even if I wanted to go, my
self-defense program is being triggered.
My tires won't move.
Come on! We came all this way together!
Can't we do anything?
Nothing we can do.
Without Buggy's speed, we won't
be able to catch up with them.
Ah! What if we could do the same as Triline-san?
That's it!
We can get caught on purpose!
It's dangerous, but worth a shot.
Alright! I'll do it.
No, if El gets caught, there's nothing we can do.
I'll be the one to do it!
- Gian, are you sure?!
- There must be other ways!
There's no time, so I'll use sound to attract them!
Wait a minute! There's no guarantee
it'll work the same way!
Shizuka-chan?!
Triline-san was captured alive.
So for girls, the possibility isn't zero!
That's true, but...
This is bad! They've noticed us!
They're coming back!
Everyone, this way! Quickly!
If it gets dangerous, I'll step in.
You guys, run!
Shizuka-chan!
Don't worry, Nobita-san. I'll succeed!
So please, come and save me later!
Nobita, hurry.
It's worked out well.
- Shizuka-san...
- Shh.
- After them.
- Yeah!
So that's the Devil's Castle...
We're finally here...
Now, let's end this!
Everyone, use these!
I wonder if we really can stop it.
It'll be fine! If we all work together...
See, when we all worked together,
I was able to finish my homework, right?
Nobita-kun...
Helping Nobita with homework
makes saving the world look easy.
- Right, Suneo?
- I guess so...
Ah... I didn't say that!
Was your homework really that difficult?
Even you, El...?
Alright, let's go!
To save Shizuka-chan and stop Poseidon!
Poseidon...!
That is not the girl.
Why did you target her and me?
We have very little data on females.
We must be perfect.
Become our data.
What is this place?
It's creepy...
Did we go somewhere we're not supposed to?
Could it be that these all are...
The Iron Cavalry.
Let's go!
I'll take them all down!
- Bang!
- Take them down!
Bang!
This is bad! We're running out of time!
The time has come.
The Earth will become a dead planet.
You're wrong!
Leave it to me and Suneo! Go!
We need to hurry before it erupts!
Defeat Poseidon and come back with Shizuka-chan!
We'll all go home together!
That's the only option, let's go!
- Nobita-kun!
- Yeah!
Ah! Don't worry about me, go ahead!
Your opponent is me!
Please, make it in time.
El and the others will definitely win!
We have to hold out till then!
This is just volcanic activity!
Atlantis perished thousands of years ago!
Any threat to Atlantis will be responded
to with the Devil's Horns.
That is how we have been programmed.
Shizuka-chan!
We're here to save you!
Nobita-san!
So, you've made it this far?
Let go of Shizuka-chan!
Silence, human!
- Woah!
- Nobita-kun!
Nobita-san!
- Ugh...
- Are you alright?!
Ah, the Bounce-Back Cape?!
Thank goodness.
A machine? This is of great interest.
But difficult to comprehend.
Why are you with the humans?
He's not a machine!
He's my friend!
That's why he's with us!
F-r-i-e-n-d...
Poseidon! This is the end!
Nobita-san!
Dora-chan!
Friends are weak.
Is it over already?
We all worked together to get this far, but...
It's all over, isn't it?
Everything...
Are you crying, Shizuka-san?
Buggy-chan?!
Don't cry, Shizuka-san.
Buggy?
He's bullying you, right?
How dare you...
How dare you?!
I won't forgive you!
Buggy-chan!
Buggy!
Why are humans so irrational?
Back then...
Even though I knew better, I
didn't make the 'correct' choice.
If you think it's right...
Is there a difference between 'right' and 'correct'?
There are times when there isn't.
What your heart thinks is right...
Isn't 'heart' your internal organ...?
No... it's different.
I don't understand what a 'heart' is.
'Right' and 'correct' aren't the same thing...
It's like...
a 'bug', isn't it?
Hm...? They stopped.
Nobita and the others did it!
It's a miracle.
Whoo! Ya did it, El!
Shizuka-chan.
Hey, this...
We need to get out of here!
Hey! This way!
Hurry!
So, it's over now, right?
Where's Buggy? Come on out.
Let's all go home.
Why're ya all so quiet?
What's going on?
Say something...
Poseidon has disappeared, and all
the Devil's Horns were also destroyed.
The world has been saved!
Everyone, the reason we were
able to defeat Poseidon is...
because of these Surface Dwellers here, and Buggy.
This was only possible because of these six friends.
And I've learned something important from them.
That is the 'heart'.
A feeling of consideration for others,
the kindness to protect one's friends.
The warmth of not abandoning someone in need.
And that heart exists within us as well.
The curse of Atlantis is gone!
This is a victory for our hearts!
And this heart is precisely the
power that will shape the future!
Let's move forward together!
Towards a world connected by hearts!
I wish Buggy could've heard this too.
Nobita-kun...
Nobita-san.
I'm sure Buggy-chan understands it too.
You're right.
Someday!
I hope that Surface Dwellers and Undersea Dwellers
can join hands and co-exist someday!
- See ya!
- Goodbye!
I'm sure that day will come!
Come on, let's go home.
Nobita-kun!
Yeah!
Goodbye. I'm looking forward to that day.
Waratte mireba ii yo
Naite mireba ii yo
It's fine to laugh,
it's fine to cry
Tekito yori chotto
Mendo wo shiyou
Don't take the easy way out,
let's take the harder road
Son'na kimi mo ii yo
Kon'na boku de ii yo
You're fine just as you are
I'm fine just as I am
Mogutta ao no naka
Honto wo shirou
In the blue that we dove into,
let's find what's real
An'na koto mo dekinaide
Unable to do things like that
Kon'na kotoni te nobashite
Still trying to do things like this
Me mawashite unadarete
Getting dizzy and hanging my head
I nemureba motonotori
If I doze off, I'll wake up at square one
Ah rakkii mo anhappii mo
Ah, lucky and unhappy
Hikarase shidaida ne nobichidjimi
It all depends on how you shine, stretch and shrink
Ah doki-doki no jikan
Ah, these heart-pounding moments
Poketto ni ire konde
I'll stuff them in my pocket
Hitori yori futari de ikite yukou
Better together than alone,
let's live together
Waratte mireba ii yo
Naite mireba ii yo
It's fine to laugh,
it's fine to cry
Tekito yori chotto
Mendo wo shiyou
Don't take the easy way out,
let's take the harder road
Son'na kimi mo ii yo
Kon'na boku de ii yo
You're fine just as you are
I'm fine just as I am
Hikatta tabi no naka
Honto wo shirou
In this dazzling journey,
let's find what's real
Hikatta ao no naka
Honto wo shiyou
In this sparkling blue,
let's do what's real
Kurushii no ni waratte itari
Laughing when it's tough
Ureshii no ni damatte itari
Staying quiet when happy
Otona wa mina abekobe de
Grown-ups all do the opposite
Kobeabe jaa hitori botchi
'No-opposite' will make me all alone
Ah happii mo anrakkii mo
Ah, happys and unluckys
Yoridori midorida ne migi-hidari
Plenty to choose from, left and right
Ah maru-batsu dotchida
Ah, right or wrong, which way to go?
Kowaikedo te nobashite
It's scary but reach out
Kowa sugitanara te wo tsunagou
If it's too scary, let's hold hands
Mayotte mireba ii yo
Tomatte mireba ii yo
It's fine to wander,
it's fine to stop
Itto yori chanto
Mattode iyou
Rather than being number one,
let's live right
Itte mireba ii yo
Susunde mireba ii yo
It's fine to go,
it's fine to move forward
Mogutta saki ga mada
Kurakute mo
Even if the place you dive into
is still dark
Tanoshii
Fun
Sabishii
Lonely
Yasashii
Gentle
Ureshii
Happy
Waratte mireba ii yo
Naite mireba ii yo
It's fine to laugh,
it's fine to cry
Tekito yori chotto
Mendo wo shiyou
Don't take the easy way out,
let's take the harder road
Son'na kimi mo ii yo
Kon'na boku de ii no
You're fine just as you are
I'm fine just as I am
Hikatta tabi no naka
Matto wo shiyou
In this dazzling journey,
let's live right
Hikatta ao no naka
Kando shiyou
In the sparkling blue,
let our hearts move
Seikai nante iikara
Don't worry about the right answer
Honto wo shiyou
Let's do what's real
Translation, Typesetting: Ommex
RAW Provider: Ender
Timing, Typesetting: Zeke Green
Everyone!
Did you have fun?
See you next time!
Heheheh...
Hot! Hot!
Spring 2027
Release Confirmed
Look forward to it!